天知道我被放逐
Don't know how many times
并自生自灭多少次了
I've been crossed off the list and left for dead.
打从一出生就开始
Guess when it first happens the day you were born,
数都数不清了
you're gonna lose count.
所以这种情况…
So this,
我早就习惯了
this ain't nothing new.
《星际传奇3》
有倒楣的日子
There are bad days,
以及无与伦比的倒楣日子
and then there are legendary bad days.
整座星球都想吃了我
Whole damn planet wanted a piece of me.
不能抛头露面
Can't stay in the open.
不能再遭到袭击
Can't risk another attack.
突如其来的暗箭最难防
It's always the punch you don't see coming that puts you down.
但我为何没留意到
But why didn't I see it?
当初他们想杀了我
Of course they were gonna try to kill me.
死亡就是他们生存的乐趣
Death is what they do for a living.
所以问题不是「出了什么事」
So the question ain't "What happened?"
而是…
The question is
「我出了什么事」
"What happened to me?"
你现在是马歇尔王了
You are the Lord Marshal now.
敌人是怎么接近的
How did they get so close?
我是如何让他们攻其不备的
How did I let them blindside me like that?
传输口 带我们到传输口
Threshold!Take us to the threshold!
是死亡教派
Necromongers.
有些人尊我为王
Some wanted to put a crown on my head.
有些人则想宰了我
Some wanted to put a noose around my neck.
好吧 想宰了我的比尊我为王的多得多
Okay, more nooses than crowns.
我需要另谋出路
I needed a way out.
换个新环境
Some new place.
或是干脆回家乡去
Or maybe just an old one.
但是如何发现你从未见过的东西
But how do you find something you've never seen?
请回到床上吧
Please, come back to bed.
有时候我认为您从未睡觉 马歇尔王
Sometimes I think you never sleep, Lord Marshal.
在有如此多烦恼的情况下
How can I sleep when I have so many…
我怎么能够安心入睡
Distractions?
那么如何才能了解一个男人的内心呢
So what is the best way to a man's heart?
在第四根肋骨和第五根肋骨之间
Between the fourth and fifth rib.
就是那个位置
That's where I usually go.
如果我想 我可以再那里打个结
I'll put a twist at the end if I wanna make sure.
如果你没有信仰 他们永远不会让你
They'll never let you stand at the threshold
进入传输口的
of Underverse without embracing the faith.
所以他们来了 刺客们
That's why they come after you, these assassins.
他们认为你变了
They think of you as something wrong.
被诅咒了 不正常了
Cursed. Illegitimate.
如果你生来就是那样 你会怎么做
What are you gonna do when you're born that way?
听见了吗
Did you hear?
警卫们还在吗
Do you think the guards are still there?
马歇尔王
Lord Marshal!
像这样
Something like that?
我是说在第四和第五根肋骨之间
I said between the fourth and fifth.
第五和第六根肋骨之间 那是空的
Fifth and sixth? Body cavity.
又交到新朋友了
Making more friends, I see.
谁把她带到这的
But who put her up to it?
哪个指挥官
Which commander?
可能是他们之中的任何一个
It could be any of many.
不要迟疑
Don't doubt it for a second,
瓦可指挥官
Commander Vaako.
马歇尔王
Lord Marshal.
瓦可 兄弟们说你失去了勇气
They say you lost your nerve, Vaako,
在那次失手之后
after that big swing and a miss.
这是他们说的吗
Is that what they say?
现在你打算如何赢回他们对你的信任
Now what are you gonna do to get that cred back?
有什么大计划
What's the big play?
引人注目的
Something splashy.
实际上
Actually,
我一直在想另一件事
I had in mind something different.
之前发生的一次战役
I've been thinking about an early campaign.
我的第一次 当我还是个男孩
My very first. I was but a boy.
我们空降到目的地 做死亡教派该做的事
We dropped from the sky and did what Necromongers do.
毁灭一切
Destruction was breathtaking.
但是我们遭遇反抗
But then we met resistance.
对方像狮子一样凶残
Ferocious like a storm of lions.
每一个人都干掉我们上百个兄弟
Each one of them killed over a hundred Necro
在他们武器失效之前
before their weapons failed.
然后又杀了30个兄弟
And then they killed another 30 more.
赤手空拳
Barehanded.
由于我们的火力和实力有数量上的优势
Our firepower and strength in numbers
最终还是赢得了那场战役
eventually won us the day.
但我还是常常想起他 最后那位伟大的战士
I can still see him, the last of those magnificent warriors,
站在他们族人的尸骨上
standing on a pile of his own.
注视着我
And he looked at me.
而我永远忘不了那双眼
And I will never forget those eyes.
跟你一样的双眼
His eyes were just like yours.
那个星球叫复仇星
The planet was Furya.
名字我知道
I know what it's called.
但你不知道位置
You just don't know where it is.
我需要航线图
I need charts. I need maps.
办不到 我需要方位
Impossible. I need a direction.
你也知道 资料都销毁了
Purged from all records, as you well know.
但是你记得位置
But you remember where.
星球太多了
So many worlds…
唯一仅存的地图
The only map left in existence
就在我的脑海中 瑞迪克
is the one that's in my head, Riddick.
你想要什么
So what do you want?
当马歇尔王
The crown?
超凡神力
Transcendence.
克朗.
Krone.
准备太空船
Break off a ship.
瑞迪克 要回家了
Riddick's going home.
超凡神力
Transcendence.
我猜这是死亡教派所说的
I guess that was Necro speak for
「永远滚出我们的飞船」
"Get the fuck off our ship and make it forever."
没关系
Fine by me.
不能怪他以复仇星当诱因
You can't blame him for dangling Furya.
家是无可取代的
Home has a certain equity.
我怪他是因为后来的事
But I do blame him for what came next.
这段遥远的旅程
It's a long way to come.
就为了这个
For this.
克朗 顶着张恶心的脸
This guy with the fucked-up face, Krone,
他应该送我们回家乡
he was supposed to be our ride home.
结果复仇星没去成 反而到了一个叫做
But instead of Furya, we wind up someplace called…
非复仇星
Not Furya.
我再次地遭人愚弄
Yet again, someone was trying to play me.
所以我们再次地…
So yet again,
为生存而杀戮
we play for blood.
凡杀过必留下痕迹 瑞迪克
You keep what you kill, Riddick!
凡杀过必留下痕迹
You keep what you kill!
我在战斗过程中失了手
Somewhere along the way, I lost a step.
太大意了
I got sloppy.
我不再身手俐落
Dulled my own edge.
我想我犯下的大错
Maybe I went and did the worst crime of all…
就是变得文明
I got civilized.
现在得重头开始
So now we zero the clock.
陪我的就只有这个无名世界
Just me and this no-name world.
我得找回我野蛮的一面
Gotta find that animal side again.
过了没多久 我就发现这里别有洞天
Before long, I realized there was a whole other world over there,
有水 有植物 有生命
of water, grass and life.
只是有个东西很碍事
Just had one thing in my way.
嘿
Hey.
快点 快来咬我吧
Come on, show me some teeth.
很会逃是吧
Escape artist, huh?
你在吃什么
What you got over there?
有福同享不是吗
Thought we shared everything
吐出来
Drop it.
待在这
Stay.
赏金猎人…
Bounty hunters.
等一下
Wait.
Wait…
等一下
Steady…
好 可以吃了
Okay, now.
应该不错
Sounds good.
嗯…
Mmm…
嗯
Mmm!
都是你的了
All yours.
上面是写狗食
It says "dog food" on it.
如果你看得懂的话
If you could read.
真是的
Come on.
好 把储备食物拿来
All right. Bring me my reserve.
你的呢
Where's yours?
要下雨了
Rain.
这是好事
It's a good thing.
没见过不代表
Just because you've never seen it before
就是坏事
doesn't mean it's a bad thing.
嘿… 别紧张
Hey, easy.
看来我们得离开了
Looks like our time is up here.
（紧急信号）
（扫描中）
（P7佣兵站紧急信号已启动）
（发现一名生还者…）
（理查雷迪克 谋杀罪逃犯）
（取回首级赏金双倍）
没人
Nothing.
再巡一次 迪亚兹
Look again, Diaz.
（留一艘太空船然后滚 否则要你的命）
教教 瑞迪克 这混球算数吧
Somebody should teach this Riddick asshole how to count.
留一艘太空船 好像我们还有一艘备用似的
"Leave one ship"? Like we've got a fucking spare laying around.
准备扎营吧
Let's crank it up.
早安 独眼龙
Good morning, Cyclops.
嘿 卢纳
Hey, Luna.
是的
Yeah.
叫她起来 踹她下床
Wake her up, kick her out of bed.
什么意思
What do you mean?
太空船太重了
We're running heavy.
她是囚犯 不是要用她来抵回程旅费吗
She's a prisoner. Wasn't she gonna pay our way back?
快超载了
We're going big now.
懂吗 要减60公斤
Okay? Cut that 60 kilos loose.
走开 不要碰我
Get away! Get away from me!
别叫 不要吵
Stop, just stop!
你又想干什么
What do you want now?
帮你解开镣铐 好吗
I'm gonna take off the restraints. Okay?
我不想解开
I don't want them off.
你想歪了
No, it's not like that.
没人会碰你的
Nobody is gonna touch you now.
桑塔纳 有别的事要忙
Santana's head is into other stuff now.
你今天走运了
Your lucky day.
别他妈的碰我
Get the fuck away from me.
好
Okay.
这是什么星球 我们在哪里
What planet is this? Where are we
这里有氧气和水
It's got air and water.
你知道这些就够了
That's all you've got to know.
我在这要怎么活 快走吧
But how am I supposed to survive… Just go.
免得他改变主意
Before he changes his mind.
我才刚喜欢上她呢
I was getting attached to her.
我的箱子呢
Now where is my box at?
我叫 桑塔纳
The name is Santana!
我是这帮人的老大
Shot-caller for this crew right here!
我这个人无所不知
I am the guy who knows all,
什么都见过 什么都不怕
sees all, beats all…
他还蛮会呛声的
Spitting it kind of strong, ain't he?
这是在诱敌
Got to bait the trap.
我特地拿箱子来装你的首级
I've come all this way to collect your head in a box!
就装在这里
Right here!
好好享受今天吧
So have yourself a fine day now,
理查德·B·瑞迪克先生
Mr. Richard B. Riddick!
我估计…
I suspect
今天便是你的死期
it will be one of your very last!
和 瑞迪克 呛声没用啦
Yeah, well, you don't need to agitate Riddick any more than, you know.
只要带着他的脑袋回去就好是吧
Any more than bringing his head back in a box would?
讨厌 抢饭碗的人又来了
Shit. Here comes the neighborhood.
世界真小
Small world.
来路不明的太空船
Unidentified vessel,
我们是Ursa五号星的Vagos帮派
this is Clan Vagos out of Ursa Five.
我们收到了紧急信号
Be advised that we are on the ground now
目前已登陆这个星球
and have responded to an emergency signal.
没什么事 不用降落了
No distress found, no need to land.
重覆 你们不必登陆这个星球
I repeat, there is no reason for you to land at this location at this time.
听到了吗
Is that clear?
你们不必登陆这个星球
No reason for you to land at this location at this time.
他妈的听不懂人话吗
What the fuck did I just say?
（留一艘太空船然后滚 否则要你的命）
这趟旅程很长 我们可以补充些水
It was a long haul. We could take on some water.
感受一下地心引力也不赖
Wouldn't mind a little true-gravity time either.
我说过了 我可以搞定
Like I was saying, I've got this.
你知道发紧急信号的是谁吧
You knew who that was, right? On the emergency beacon?
不知道就不会来了
Wouldn't be here if I didn't.
有人来支援还不高兴吗
The concept of back-up still has no appeal to you?
我的手下能搞定任何人
My besties here can ball with anyone.
我可不是说你们喔
No disrespect for your crew, of course,
你们的制服看起来挺炫的
who look strong, too, in those matchy-matchy outfits.
糟了 我不知道有主题服装
Shit. Didn't know there was a dress code.
真的耶
Yeah, right?
我不是故意要踩你的线
Well, it's not my intention to jump another man's claim.
如果不介意 我们拉张椅子
If you don't mind, maybe we'll just pull up a chair
在旁边观赏一会
and spectate for a while.
如果介意呢
What if I do?
兄弟 这是公用太空站 任何佣兵都能来
Well, this is a co-op station, pal. It's open to all Mercs.
对了 我叫做… 太迟了
By the way, my name is… "Too late."
你就叫「太迟了」
That's your name."Too Late."
我才不让你进来搅局
And I don't need you stepping all over my dick here, my friend.
不如这样好了
Well, I'll tell you what.
我绝不出手 除非你找我帮忙 怎么样
I won't lift a finger to help until you come ask me for it. How's that?
我之前勘查过这里
I was scoping this out earlier.
南方五公里处有岩洞群
It's a cave system. Five clicks south.
可以去看看
Might be worth a look.
嘿 太迟了
Hey, Too Late.
拆一个燃料夹
Need to pull a node from your ship
跟我的放在一起
and store it right here next to mine. Okay?
是吗 为什么
Really? Why is that?
瑞迪克 为了逃才启动信号 对吧
Riddick triggered the beacon to get off-world, right?
基本上 他是在叫计程车
Basically, he was calling a taxi.
所以呢
And…
太空船正好用来当陷阱
And a ship would make a sweet trap, right?
封闭空间 铜墙铁壁 像监狱一样
Confined space, metal walls, jail cell.
很酷吧
Is cool, huh?
你是不是真的常遇到
Is it true half the people you meet
智障
are below average intelligence?
得准备好等他来 明白吗
Got to make sure the ship stays grounded when he comes for them, okay?
快点
Come on.
达尔 拆一个燃料夹下来
Dahl, pull a node from the ship.
让我来
I'll do it…
喔
Ooh!
喔…
Ooh…
（警告 会向外爆炸）
就等你了 瑞迪克
Any time now, Riddick.
我告诉你 根本是瓮中捉鳖
I'm telling you, this is total overkill.
我们出动了11个人
What? Eleven of us out here now?
顶多四个人就够了
Should have been a four-man op, tops.
少在那里触霉头 这样很不好
You are jinxing our janx, man. And that ain't cool.
我才不管别人怎么说 他才一个人
Hey, I don't give a shit what they say. He's one guy.
随便你怎么说
Whatever you say, man.
他才一个人
He's one guy.
真讨厌
Man…
我们只能在一颗月亮下这样杀时间
So I guess that's what passes for a fucking moon on this planet.
晚上会很暗
It's gonna be a dark night.
这对他有利
Advantage, him.
或许他想削减你的体力 逼着你不能睡觉
Maybe he's gonna wear you down first. Force you to go without sleep.
没看到我在忙吗
Can't you see I'm busy?
我只是分享意见
I'm just sharing my thoughts.
你分享完了
Well, now that you have,
我可以礼貌地
can I politely invite you to
请你滚蛋吗
step off my fucking porch?
我去准备关门
I'll start rotating down.
有事就叫我
You let me know, huh?
我一拿到他的脑袋就会跟你说
As soon as I have his head in a box, I will let you know.
29D区 请待命
Grid 29D. Stand by, stand by.
表哥 你看到什么
What you got, cuz?
一只像狗的东西
Aha, some dingo-dongo thing.
对 我也看到了
Yeah. I see it now.
要不要射杀
You want me to pop it?
一枪解决 用灭音器
Knock it down. One shot suppressed.
干得好 迪亚兹 真是振奋士气啊
Nice work, Diaz. Encouraging.
眼睛被东西挡住了
Had something in my eye.
那叫瞄准镜
It's called a scope.
下次记得用
Try next time.
搞得定吧
You got this, right?
别占用我的频道
Will you get off my freaking frequency!
这里发生什么事
What the fuck is going on here?
真他妈感谢主
Thank fucking God!
滚开啦
Fuck off!
卢比奥 我现在要过去 得更换故障的感应器
Rubio, coming your way now. Gotta swap out a bad sensor.
登记的和目前库存的
What was here versus what was found.
有出入吗
How does it square?
都很好 吗啡没了
Pretty good. I mean, the morphine's gone,
每次都是这个先用完
but that's always the first thing to go.
这里挺奇怪的
That was a bit weird, though.
42英吋的利齿捕兽夹
"A predator restraint with 42-inch offset jaws."
原本有六个 全没了
Six listed, zero found.
不见这些还挺怪的
That is an odd thing to go for a walk.
不过太空站常有东西被偷
Yeah, but, Boss, you know how shit goes missing from these stations.
一不景气就有人偷东西变卖
One bad year and guys are ripping shit off for salvage.
嘿 桑塔纳
Hey, Santana?
我来之前你有搜查过这里吧
You did sweep the area before I got here, right?
搜查什么
Sweep for what?
我只想确定没人设陷阱陷害我们
I just want to make sure no one has set any traps for us.
检查5Q区
5Q.
懂我的意思吧
Understand what I'm saying?
陷阱 什么样的陷阱
Traps? What kind of traps?
有利齿的那种
The kind with jaws.
别碰那个东西
Don't touch that fucking thing!
怎么了
What?
护胸盔甲
Up-armor.
妈的
Shit!
准备出动
Ready. Ready.
不要动…
Stay put, stay put, stay put, stay put!
哦哈
Oopah!
谁在那里鬼吼鬼叫啊
Who the hell was that screaming and why?
努涅斯 带扫描探测器来
Nunez, break out the sweep gear.
找出外面还有多少这种大陷阱
And figure out how many of these big-ass traps
我们得离开这里
we got out here, okay?
搞不好左上半边
I'm thinking maybe the whole upper left quad
都是陷阱区
is some kind of fucking mine field.
赶快去 听到没有
You got to do that now, okay, Nunez?
努涅斯 听到没有
Copy that, Nunez?
努涅斯？
Nunez?
惨了 情况很不妙
This is bad. This is very bad.
努涅斯？努涅斯？
Nunez? Nunez?
给我闭嘴 混蛋
Shut the fuck up, puto!
他的对讲机坏了 看着他
His radio just crapped out. Someone get eyes on him.
叫他回13H区 快去
Make sure he's right where he should be, 13-H. Go, go, go!
就是这里
Right here.
13H区 他应该在这里才对
13-H. He's supposed to be right fucking…
这叫瓮中捉鳖 还嫌11个人太多
So this was overkill, huh? Eleven of us, too many. Yeah.
很了解 瑞迪克 是吧
You know all about Riddick, right?
或许你应该收回那句话
Well, maybe you need to take that shit back!
收回触霉头的话 懂了没
Take the jinx off our janx. You understand me?
法尔科 那才是你该做的
That's what you need to do, Falco.
你得收回那句倒楣话
You need to unjinxelate our fucking janx!
现在别搞我
Don't mess with me now.
那是什么
Hey. Hey, what is it? What is it?
退后 是我
Get back! It's me, it's me.
他杀了法尔科
He's got Falco!
准备应战 你们俩留守
Jock up, but you're staying home.
没我的命令 谁都不准出去
No one's going out there until I say so.
人员阵亡 他杀了法尔科
Man down, he's got Falco.
被发现了…
Compromise, compromise.
他是怎么办到的
How the fuck did he do that?
他站在这 而我却没看到
Never ever saw him, man. He was right here and I never…
那太空船呢 他在上面吗
What about the ship? Is he on it?
他的目标不是太空船 是我们
He's not coming for the ships, he's coming for fucking us!
快开枪
Just fucking shoot! Shoot!
一晚就死了三个
One night, three dead.
这样下去可不行
Not sure I'm loving this trend.
是两死一失踪
Two dead, one missing.
没错 死了三个
Exactly. Three dead.
换个方式来看
Well, look at it this way, boys.
大家刚好可以挤一艘船
We might all fit on one ship now.
迪亚兹
Diaz!
把其他陷阱都拿回来
Get those other traps back there.
卢纳 替他们祷告一下
Luna, say something Bible-like over these bodies.
好吧 或许
Okay, maybe,
应该重新来过
we zero this out.
你到底叫什么
What is your tag anyway?
你终于想知道了
So now you wanna know my name.
我不确定该不该讲
Well, I'm not sure I'm gonna say.
因为被你知道名字的都挂了
Because everyone you know by name, Santana, winds up dead.
你要打扫吗
You gonna clean this shit up?
不好意思
Excuse me. Wow.
小心被偷袭
Watch out for surprise attacks.
或许
Maybe…
或许我们应该同心协力了 对吧
Maybe it's time to start merging assets, right?
所以你在找我帮忙
So this is you asking for my help?
我只是需要你的武器
This is me saying that I may need some of your gear.
如果你的人必须跟着武器
If some of your guys happen to come attached to that gear,
我能理解 反正就这样
I will understand that's the way it's gotta be.
所以你只是要借武器
So you're asking for my gear's help?
More like that.
莫斯…
Moss…
武器说「不要」 很难搞
The gear's saying, "Nah." Bitch.
你听到啦
There's your answer.
你到底想怎样
What the fuck do you want, man?
这样吧 我让你加入我们 桑塔纳
You know what? I'm gonna fold you in, Santana.
不过 达尔 听命于我
But I give orders to Dahl.
而你则听命于 达尔
And Dahl's gonna give orders to you.
以后的指挥链就是这样
And that's the chain of command from this point forward.
我怎么好像不太满意
Why am I not loving this plan so far?
我懂了… 你知道原因吗
Oh, I know, I know. You know why?
因为这样子很鸟
Because it sucks ass and swallows!
我才不听你那小婊子的命令
I'm not taking orders from your pet whore
她还以为我不敢还手
who thinks I won't smack her right back…
我不搞男人
I don't fuck guys.
但遇到欠搞的 我会搞死他
Occasionally I fuck 'em up if they need it.
计划是这样的 桑塔纳 你先在这待命
Here's what's gonna happen, Santana. You're gonna take a back seat.
我保证会逮到瑞迪克
We'll track Riddick down, I promise.
但我要留活口
But I want him alive.
给我一天时间 之后他随你处置
You give me a day, and after that he's yours to kill.
你要把赏金让给我
You're giving me the bounty?
扣掉团员薪资和燃料费 剩下的归你 就这样
You pay my crew, fuel costs, the rest is yours. That's the deal.
你找 瑞迪克 干嘛 他可不是一般罪犯
What is Riddick for you? Not just some convict.
你的目的何在 你为什么来这里
What do you want? Why are you here?
你是谁
Who are you?
我叫 约翰
My name is Johns.
封锁太空船 把气垫车移到甲板上
Lock down those ships, get those hogs on deck.
我跟莫斯和拉克斯波坐一台
I will ride with Moss and Lockspur.
只准带非致命性电击枪和白磷手榴弹
I want a non-lethal load-out, L.O.D.'s and phosphor frags to start with.
他是个在夜晚狩猎的人 我们则要在白天行动
This is a man that hunts by night. We'll take it to him by day.
迪亚兹 瓦格斯
Diaz! Vargas!
带我去上一个人被杀的地点
Show me the spot of the last kill.
是某种狗
Some kind of canine.
嘿 迪亚兹 发现一只狗
Hey, Diaz, I got a dog here.
是昨晚那只吗
Is it the same dingo-dongo thing from last night?
不是 那只被我们杀了
Nah, I'm pretty sure we killed that one.
可能是同一只
Could be the same one.
是同一只
The same.
达尔 用狙击枪和钡弹
Dahl, get your sniper rifle and barium rounds now.
距离一千五百米
1, 500 meters.
它可能只是看到洞就躲
Could be just the first hole it found.
动物受惊吓会躲到熟悉的地方
A stressed animal is gonna run to ground it knows.
此外 这里有人类的费洛蒙
Besides, I'm getting human pheromones.
瑞迪克
Riddick!
停火…
Dial down, dial down, dial down!
是桑塔纳的人
Santana's guy.
法尔科
Falco.
糟糕 我们杀了人质吗
Shit. Did we just kill a hostage?
我整整找了瑞迪克十年
I've been hunting Riddick for 10 years.
他不玩人质这一套
The concept of a hostage has no appeal to him.
法尔科 早就死了
Falco was already dead.
他只是用这招来拖时间
This is just some fucking sideshow to buy more time.
他妈的…
Whoa! Fuck…
靠
Shit.
真是出师不利
Just dropped some mud right there.
如果瑞迪克不在这里…
So if Riddick isn't here…
达尔 听得到吗 有人听到吗
Dahl? Dahl, do you copy? Does anyone copy?
达尔 你在吗
Dahl, you there?
嘭
Boom.
你在对我抛媚眼吗
Were you just perving out on me somehow?
宝贝 祝你心想事成
May all your dreams come true, baby.
给你两分钟 到外面站岗
You've got two minutes. I want you out on fucking watch.
卢纳
Luna!
别看着我 掩护我 那才是你来的目的
Don't watch me. Watch my back. That's what you're here for.
向前走两步 我说两步
Take two steps forward. Two.
记住 他神出鬼没
Remember, he could be anywhere.
我是约翰 站内的人快回答
This is Johns to any-goddamn-body at the station.
我要你们看好置物柜 看好燃料夹
I want you to keep an eye on that locker. Keep an eye on the node.
瑞迪克 可能会用欺敌战术
Riddick may have made an end run.
我大概七分钟后到 大家小心一点
My ETA is seven minutes. But watch your back.
小贱人 你跑去哪了
All right, you little bitch.
两分钟到了 你到底要不要去
Your two minutes are up. You gonna do what I tell you to do?
听说瑞迪克在附近
Rumor is Riddick might be in the vicinity.
应该检查一下置物柜
Thought I should just check on the locker.
去外面 戴上夜视镜 然后找出那个混蛋
Get outside, get on your optics, and get after this fucker!
他又不在这里
You're not gonna find him here.
老实说 达尔 我觉得我们挺像的
Actually, Dahl, I think we have something in common.
我也不搞男人
I don't fuck guys either.
你得看看这个
You need to see this.
（一物换一物）
他写的吗
He wrote that?
他破坏了整个通讯系统
He took out our deep space communications. All of it.
那是谁的血 那边有 这边也有
And whose blood is that? There… Here…
那里也有
Over there…
我非得再扁他一顿 对不起
I had to kick his ass again. Sorry.
才怪
Not really.
去他的
Fuck it.
咱们来检查一下
Let's take a look at this.
住手
Stop.
那把钥匙有离开过你的脖子吗
That key leave your neck?
从来没有
Never.
一物换一物的唯一可能性
Well, the only reason to write "fair trade"
就是他拿了柜内的东西
is if he got into that locker and he took something out.
我们需要的东西 例如燃料夹
Something that we need, like a power node,
然后再交换他要的东西
which he could then swap for something he needs.
这么费功
All that? Wow.
可能性很低
Highly unlikely.
我跟你解释一下 桑塔纳
Let me join the fucking dots for you, Santana.
这是我的推论 如果他真的打开过
Here's what I'm saying. If he did get in there somehow,
他绝对能重锁并更改密码
he was in a position to relock it and change the code.
密码可能改掉了 桑塔纳
Could be entering the wrong shit, Santana.
所以说…
So,
你认为在几个小时内
do you think sometime during the last few hours
他偷拿走我脖子上的钥匙
he got this off my neck without me noticing,
开了锁再挂回我的脖子上
did whatever he did, put the fucking key back
而我却浑然不知吗
on my fucking neck without me fucking noticing?
你是这个意思吗
Is that what you're saying?
这想法是从哪来的 从独角兽的屁眼里吗
Where did you get that theory from? A unicorn's ass?
他可不是浪得虚名
There's a reason he is who he is.
他是个罪犯 又不是什么通灵大法师
He's a convict. Not some Zulu warlock.
既然你这么说
You know what you know.
真荒唐
This is crazy.
真他妈的扯 前三圈都没问题
This is fucking crazy. The first three clicks were good.
也没有爆炸
It did not go off.
俄罗斯轮盘也可能玩到三轮
You can get three clicks in Russian roulette.
难保第四轮不出事
Doesn't mean you get four, motherfucker.
说真的 桑塔纳
You know what, Santana?
这次我终于相信你了 你稳的啦
For once I actually agree with you. I think you're good.
少啰嗦
Shut up.
你 你认为我们稳吗
You. Do you think we're good?
对
Yeah.
表哥 我觉得你很稳
I think you're good, cuz.
你很稳啦 只要再男人一点就好
You're fucking good. Just butch up.
听起来你比较适合吧 女同
Sounds like your department, lesbo.
我才不要开
I'm not opening that thing.
你非开不可
Oh, yes, you fucking are!
死都不要
I'm so fucking not!
用用你们的大脑
Hey, hey, hey! Use your fucking brains!
别帮瑞迪克 杀自己人
We are not gonna do Riddick's work for him!
通通放下武器
Put your weapons down.
你们自己看
And have a look at that.
他来过这里
He was here.
就在那里
Right fucking there.
桑塔纳 把剑放下
Santana, put your fucking sword away.
那就别开吧
Don't fucking open it, then.
现在的问题是不开柜子…
Well, the problem with that, Santana, we never open that locker,
我们就走不了
and we never leave.
让我敬畏的主赐与我力量
The strength of my life of Whom shall I be afraid.
第四圈
Four.
试试第五圈
Five.
接下来
And…
不好意思
Oops.
可惜不是我吓的
Wish I'd have thought of that.
第六圈
Six!
Six.
哼
Huh.
第六圈
Six.
桑塔纳 你真是开锁大师 算你厉害
You are a shit storm trooper, Santana. I'll give you that.
你战胜了死神
You beat the devil this time.
我还以为他不敢开
Didn't actually think he was gonna do it.
这是个征兆
This is a sign.
太棒了
Ah, sweet.
我相信这是个征兆
I believe this is a sign.
上帝可能希望我们拿回燃料
It may be that the good Lord wants us to take these nodes
然后立即离开这个星球
and flee this planet just as soon as we can.
我才是幸运星
That's my good luck charm.
小鬼 你入错行了
Wrong business, kid.
其实我还蛮希望爆炸的
You know, I was kind of hoping the bomb would go off.
我们用手榴弹封他的巢穴 让他有家归不得
So we sealed up his cave with some phosphor frags here, so he can't go back.
人就像动物 他会躲到熟悉的地方
And just like an animal, he's gonna head to known ground.
但他绝对有三 四个脱逃路线
But we're gonna find he's got three or four lairs out there.
我们从这一点向外搜查 就是这里
So we'll radius out from this point, here.
包括那台对讲机 清单上写有三支对讲机
Now radio comms… I saw three repeaters listed in inventory.
通通找出来 调成正常通话距离
Find them. Set them up at regular intervals.
绝对不能再失去通讯
I never want to be out of touch like that again.
你怕我吗
Are you scared of me?
怕
Yeah.
他们怕我吗
Are they scared of me?
大家都怕你
Yes, they're scared of you.
你们该怕的不是我
Maybe you're all scared of the wrong thing.
拉克斯波 把飙骑全部锁好
Lockspur, I want you to lock down those hogs, all right?
他要是再快就更抓不到了
I don't want this guy any more mobile than he already is.
达尔 我帮你找到一个好据点
Now, Dahl, I spotted a nice little nest for you.
这边和那些矮丘里
Right here and in these low hills.
莫斯？
Moss?
我刚才看到他
I just saw him.
什么
Say again?
我刚才看到他
I just saw him.
达尔 我要你看紧太空船
Dahl, I want you to sit on this ship!
迪亚兹 去把太空船锁好
Diaz, make sure your ship is locked down!
其他人守好四周
The rest of you get on the fucking perimeter
互相看紧一点
and keep your eyes on each other!
桑塔纳 燃料夹被他拿走了
Santana! He got the fucking nodes!
我知道 暴风雨快来了
I know. It's coming
我们干脆合并燃料夹
So then we just combine nodes.
把那艘船的拿来这里用
Pull one from that ship, put it in this ship, you know?
燃料都一样 对吧
Amps is amps, right?
重点不是燃料，而是适不适合太空船用
It's not about amps. It's about what each ship is rated to handle.
差个零点几焦耳，所有电路板就会烧掉
You miss by even a few milli-joules, you fry every chip you've got.
好 那就快看合不合啊
Okay, so figure out the difference, and just do it.
快破解这个鬼东西
Jailbreak the fucking thing.
我可以帮你恶补一下
I could give you a crash course
热平衡和交换能
on thermodynamic equilibrium and energy exchange right now,
或是你可以直接听我的话
or maybe you just want to take my goddamn word for it…
明白了
I get it. I get it.
这两艘船不通用 不夺回燃料夹就走不了
The ships are incompatible. We're not gonna fly without the nodes back.
为何感觉像在自灭威风
Why do I feel like we just cut off our own nuts here?
因为事实正是如此
Probably because we did.
干脆给我一辆飙骑 还有两天份的食物
How about I take one of those jet hogs, two days' worth of food
我亲自去抓那个王八蛋
and go out and hunt this fucker down myself?
烂点子 迪亚兹
Bad idea, Diaz.
想找 瑞迪克 单挑吗
One-on-one with Riddick?
我也许能重新启动紧急信号
I might be able to get the emergency beacon working again.
就像是救护车叫救护车 对吧
That's like an ambulance calling for an ambulance, isn't it?
是支援在请求支援
It's back-up for the fucking back-up. We can't.
我以为只有他受困在这
I thought he was the one stranded here.
看来你猜错了
Yeah, well, looks like you thought wrong.
支援要等很久
Long wait for back-up.
假如你们想
In case you were thinking about
修好信号求救
fixing the beacon and calling for help.
是法尔科 的分机
Falco's radio.
瑞迪克 我才不需要支援
Riddick, I don't give a fuck about the back-up.
因为我还有各式各样的装备
Because I've still got all kinds of gear
可以立刻送你上西天
that can ruin your day in a hurry.
去找个新的洞躲吧
So you go find another fucking cave.
你就继续跑 继续躲吧
You keep runnin', you keep hidin'.
我懒得管
Doesn't matter me none.
因为最后都会被我找到
Because in the end, I will find you!
往南边看
Look south.
真不敢相信
I don't believe it.
这家伙真有种
The balls on this fucking guy.
达尔 看好这里
Dahl, keep an eye on things here.
我要做什么
What should I do?
蹲低点
Stay low.
快点 快点
Come on. Come on.
你们两个放下武器
Both of you drop.
我的人头值多少钱
So what's the bounty at?
不知道也不在乎 这不是我来的目的
I don't know. I don't care. It's not why I'm here.
那个大智障肯定知道
I bet the big jamoke knows.
对 我知道确切金额
Yeah. I know exactly what it is.
我只知道带人头回去是双倍
What I do know is that it's double if you're brought back dead.
这倒没听过
That's new.
够支付你们的葬礼吗
Will it be enough to pay for your funerals?
我有兴趣的是…
What I'm interested in
编号M344/G那个荒僻星球
is a little backwater place with a system code M-344/G.
我想知道十年前发生什么事
I want to know what happened there 10 years ago.
父亲出现了
The father.
约翰 老爹
Big Daddy Johns.
没错 你说得对
Yeah, that's right.
你大老远跑来就为了找我
And you traveled all this way just to see me.
我受宠若惊
I'm flattered.
族谱不知道怎么写
It's kind of strange not knowing
总觉得怪怪的
what to put down in the family bible.
为此牺牲三条命也蛮奇怪的
It's kind of strange three guys have to die just so that you can hear…
不… 别把他们的死算在我头上
No, no, no. You don't get to put that shit on me.
全都得指向你
Those kills are on you.
我有预感「指」向我的不止这个
I have a feeling that's not the only thing on me right now.
对 我有钡弹 电击弹 爆裂弹
Okay, got barium shells, stab-shock, explosive tip.
你选哪一个 钡弹还是电击弹
What do you want, barium or stab-shock?
动物麻醉针
Horse tranq.
好吧…
Okay.
我不想打扰你们讨论八百年前的事
I hate to interrupt this discussion about ancient history,
不过我应该过来自我介绍一下
but maybe I should step in right here and introduce myself.
我的大名是… 箱子男
My name is… Box Boy.
你说啥
Say what?
就是你想把我的头装进箱子吧 不是吗
You are the guy who said that he was gonna put my head in a box. Right?
这个嘛… 是我… 碎碎念而已啦
Well, that was me spitting noise.
可是你真的有带箱子
But you do have a box.
我有… 箱子吗
Do I have a box?
我好像有看到
Thought I saw one.
我当然有带箱子 老兄 每个人都有带箱子
I mean, of course I've got a box. Everyone's got a box, man.
连迪亚兹都有个超大的箱子
Even Diaz has a fucking huge box.
很好
Good.
我们会用得到
We're gonna use it.
三个挂了 剩八个
Three down, eight left.
通常我会继续杀下去
Now, normally I'd just keep going.
六个挂了… 再来是九个
Six down… Nine down…
懂了吧
You get where I'm going with this.
但现在情况不同
But things are changing here
没人想在这待超过24小时
and nobody wants to be on this planet 24 hours from now.
所以我建议大家有志一同
So I suggest we make it work.
你要来个君子协定吗
What do you want, a gentleman's agreement?
我放一个燃料夹在外面 你去拿
I'll leave one node out in the open. You take it.
剩下的燃料和另一艘船归我
The other node and the other ship are mine.
嘿 等一下
Hey, wait, wait.
现在在玩什么游戏 智障宾果吗
What are we playing here, retard bingo? What?
一开始就是这样啊
That was on the table from the start…
别管一开始了
Forget the start.
你该关心的是结局
It's the end you want to think about now.
看到没有
See that?
我让你考虑到雨下到太空站
I'll give you till that rain hits that station.
自己注意时间
That's your clock.
箱子男…
"Box Boy"…
达尔 快开枪 快
Dahl! Do it now! Now!
再一发
Again!
他不会昏倒的
He's not going down.
继续射 达尔
Do it again, Dahl!
他这不就昏倒了
Just go down.
让我来 达尔
I got this, Dahl.
瑞迪克
Riddick.
瑞迪克？
Riddick?
约翰？
Johns?
你开始用链子打俘虏了吗
We beating men in chains now?
好 从最早说起 先说明一下…
Okay, from the beginning. For the historical record…
Gratzner 猎人号
The Hunter Gratzner.
我儿子就是用这艘商用飞行舰
That's the commercial vessel my son uses
运送你回监狱的
to transport you back to the slammer.
但那艘船却在M344/G附近发出求救讯号
But that ship sends a distress call somewhere near M-344/G.
那是个荒僻的星系
It's a backwater system,
两个太阳和一个适合人居住的星球
with two suns, one habitable planet.
他有在坠机中存活吗
Does he survive the crash?
之后几小时出现了很戏剧化的发展
Big drama the next few hours.
不过无论发生什么事 不管他们说什么
But whatever happens, no matter what they tell you,
都千万别让他们松绑我
don't let 'em take these chains off me.
「他们」 谁是「他们」
Them? Who's "them"? Who are you talking…
你知道你在跟谁说话吗
Do you know who you're talking to here?
你在瞪我吗
That was for me?
一旦解开这些手铐…
When the chains come off…
有完没完
Jesus Christ.
箱子男
Box Boy,
五秒内你先死
you go in the first five seconds.
真的吗
Really?
你打算怎么杀 打嘴炮吗
And you plan on killing me with what, your mouth?
用那把金光闪闪的刀
That shiny blade.
我倒想见识一下
I'd love to see you try.
先说明一下…
For the historical record,
他存活了
he made it.
只有你们两个存活
So it's just you and him?
原本有
Was, uh,
跟这里差不多的人数
about the same number you see here in this room.
有多少人逃出去
So how many made it off?
三个
Three.
但是没有他
But not him?
没有
No.
所以在坠机和你离开前这段时间…
So between the time of the crash and the time you leave that planet,
我儿子死了
my son dies.
我可以有把握地假设是你杀的 对不对
And I can safely assume it's at your hands. Is that right?
我在浪费他妈的时间
I'm wasting my fucking time here!
有任何临终遗愿吗
You grant any last wishes?
我是指你
I was referring to you.
并不是手铐不性感
Not that the chains aren't a hot look, but no.
我才不要在他们面前骑你
I'm not gonna straddle you in front of all these guys.
如果我先杀了他们呢
What if I killed all of 'em first?
冷静点 小子
Easy, boy.
麻醉药还有一大堆
There's a lot more tranq where that came from.
达尔 告诉我窗外有什么
Tell me what you see outside that window, Dahl.
独眼龙装备 两艘太空船
Cyclops unit, two ships,
还有几具装袋的尸体
couple dead guys in plastic.
没看到其他东西吗
And you don't see anything else?
没有
Nothing else.
看到时通知我
Let me know when you do.
你的指甲很漂亮
Love those toenails, by the way.
是吗
Yeah?
侵略系粉红色
Predator Pink.
跟你的乳头很搭
Matches your nipples.
我们干嘛听这个大淫虫废话
Why are we even listening to this big fuckstick?
可以拜托直接砍了他的头吗
Can we just detach his head, please?
听着
Here's what's gonna happen.
接下来的60秒
The next 60 seconds,
你的头会被装进那个箱子
you're gonna watch your own head drop into that box.
什么都…
Nothing,
什么都阻止不了你下地狱
nothing is gonna keep you from that special place in hell.
或许死前的最后一分钟
Maybe in the last minute of your life, you want to be something more
你可以他妈的文明点
than a goddamn savage!
好好回答我的问题
Gimme some fucking answers!
求求你
Please!
我讲的你有要补充什么吗
Is there anything you'd like to add on the subject I just raised?
时间到了
Time's up.
时间的确到了
Time is up.
他是你的了
He's all yours.
压住他
Hold him down.
大概是更多狗来了
More dingo-dongos maybe.
去他的
Fuck it.
我知道是什么
I know what's coming.
是你叫来的 这群蛇怪
Called to find you. The serpents…
打灯
Spotlight!
正如我所说
Like I said,
你们该怕的不是我
it ain't me you gotta worry about.
什么东西 外面有什么
What is it? What's out there?
不知道
I don't know.
是可怕的东西
Fucked up or something out there.
不太对劲 朝我们过来了
It ain't right. It's coming our way.
不管是什么东西 其实没那么难解决嘛
Whatever they are, they ain't so hard to kill.
搞什么鬼
What the fuck?
妈的
Fuck!
拜托别再开洞了
No more holes, please.
听着
Now here's what's gonna happen.
接下来的60秒 你们要松绑我
In 60 seconds you're gonna take these chains off me.
我们要取回燃料夹然后离开这个星球
We're gonna make a play for those nodes and get off this rock.
但如果在过程中… 情况变得很糟时…
But somewhere along the line, when it gets really bad,
约翰
Johns
就会像他儿子一样认输
is gonna fold just like Little Johns did.
等一切结束后
Then when it's all over
你们剩下的人就等着被捡尸体
and the rest of you are ready for Dead Animal Pickup,
我会好好地「深入」达尔
I'm gonna go balls deep into Dahl.
只因为她请我这样做
But only because she asked me to.
用她的「甜嘴」问
Sweet-like.
「情况变糟」是什么意思
What does he mean, "When things go bad"?
这样还不算糟吗
What? This doesn't qualify as bad?
现在到底是怎样 状况到底有多糟
What the fuck is happening? How fucked are we?
谁知道雨会下多久
Who knows how long it will rain?
或是我杀了多少只
Or just how many of them are buried out there?
他的眼睛看得一清二楚 却什么也不讲
He saw it. He saw it with those eyes of his and he didn't tell us what.
一艘船归你 一艘船归我
One ship for you, one for me.
我要确定能取回燃料夹
I need to know that these nodes are retrievable.
而我要确定我们一言为定
And I need to know we have a deal.
一言为定
We got a deal.
不准放开他
The chains stay on.
我们旁观吧
Why don't we sit this one out?
好吧
Okay. Okay.
起来…
Up, up, up…
乖狗狗
Good doggie.
噢
Oh!
我的妈呀
Holy shit.
是啊
Yeah.
还是放了他吧
Let's cut him loose.
只花了五秒
That was five seconds.
我一向说话算话
I like to be a man of my word.
约翰 你呢
How about you, Johns?
上帝将派天使保护我 让我永远活在…
For He shall give His angels charge over me, keep me in
他的恩典中 闭嘴啦 卢纳
all His grace as long as I live. Shut the noise, Luna.
我觉得天使来保护我了
You know, I think the angels are here protecting me.
如果他们在这里看守我
And if they're here, watchin' over me,
或许会带我们离开… 这个鬼地方
maybe they'll deliver us all from this crazy, evil place.
别在那里吓人 给我闭嘴
That shit is creeping everybody out, so shut the fuck up.
你才闭嘴 别凶那个孩子
You shut the fuck up, Vargas. Leave the kid alone.
哪里跑来的 我的老天
Where the hell did that… Jesus Christ!
别射…
No, no, no!
死疯子 你有什么毛病
What the fuck is wrong with you, you crazy bastard?
你差点杀了我
You could have killed me!
射中了 不是吗
Got it, didn't I?
瓦格斯 起来
Vargas, get up.
瓦格斯 快起来 我们走
Vargas, get up. Come on, let's go.
瓦格斯 快点 小伤而已 走吧
Vargas, come on, man. Walk it off.
只是小只的而已
Let's go. It's just a little one.
小只的最恐怖
Small ones are the worst.
它们的毒液最多
They save the most venom.
孩子
And kid,
别烦上帝了
leave God out of this.
接下来的事他才不管
He wants no part of what happens next.
我忘了跟你说
I forgot to mention,
你不准用武器
there's no weapons for you.
你会骑这种车吗
You think you can ride one of these things?
我早在无数关头玩过命了
I'll ride it like I stole it.
我骑旁边掩护你
I'll take flank.
如果 瑞迪克 独自回来
If Riddick comes back here without us,
你就照基本原则杀了他
you go ahead, you kill him on general principle.
是在我该干他之前或之后
Is that before or after I'm supposed to fuck him?
你这个混帐王八蛋 只会在旁边看
You asshole motherfucker! Just sittin' there watchin'!
我原本可以掩护你 但你说 「不准用武器」
Would have covered you, but you said, "No weapons."
你有多想要那些燃料夹 约翰
How bad you want those nodes, Johns?
你应该没有像这样安葬他吧
I don't suppose you took the time to do this for him, huh?
你可能会感到很震惊
This may come as a shock to you, Johns,
但我并没杀你儿子
but I didn't ghost your son.
他应该是自杀的
He seemed set on killin' himself.
什么意思
What the fuck does that mean?
是吗啡
Morphine.
你儿子吗啡上瘾
Your son liked his morphine.
一天打两次
Liked it twice a day.
你不知道自己儿子是毒虫吗
Didn't know your son was a junkie?
小约翰 跟其他佣兵一样
Johns was like most Mercs.
看起来勇敢又正直
They look all stand-up and do-right
深入了解后才发现有东西没了
until you cut them open and you find something missing.
就他来说 他没种
In his case, a spine.
我不需要听这些屁话 这不是我认识的他
I don't have to listen to this shit! That's not the man I knew.
是你不了解你儿子
Then you didn't know your son.
他为了活命…
He wanted to kill a kid.
还想牺牲小孩子
To save his own skin.
让我很不爽
I had a problem with that.
你是要我相信
You expect me to believe
我儿子会为求自保而杀小孩吗
my son was gonna kill a child to save his own life?
吗啡让人意志薄弱 失去良知
Morphine makes the brain soft. Heart weak.
我死都不相信
I don't fuckin' buy it!
我不相信我儿子是坏人
I just can't believe that my son's the bad guy
是你编出来的胡言乱语
in this fuckin' demented fairy tale of yours.
我没理由骗你
No reason to lie now.
约翰.
Johns.
至少我们有一方坦承
Either one of us.
多谢你帮我杀了其他人
Thanks for startin'the killing spree for me, Riddick.
其他的我来就好
But I'll take it from here.
大智障
Jamoke.
你埋藏那把刀是为了杀我吗
So that blade you buried was meant for me?
只要是该死的就杀
Anyone who deserved it, really.
问题大了 瑞迪克，
We've got a problem, Riddick,
因为这里有两个燃料夹
because I've got two nodes here.
但只有一辆飙骑
We've got one hog.
而我死都不要再坐你后面
And I sure as shit am not ridin' bitch with you again.
一辆飙骑
One hog?
你确定吗
You sure about that, Johns?
他把涡轮针拔掉了
He pulled the goddamn turbine pin!
你现在才发现啊
You just figured that out?
迪亚兹 原本想拿了燃料夹就杀我
Diaz was gonna take the nodes for himself and ghost me.
他打算弃你而去
He was gonna leave you out here alone.
现在怎么办
So what now?
也只能徒步行动了
Now we switch to our ground game.
瞧瞧是不是「犬子无虎父」
Let's see if that lack o spine runs in the family.
再上膛
Reload!
小心头
Watch your head.
快走
Go!
有东西接近
I got inbound.
拿去
Take this!
只有你一个人吗
Is it just you?
快装进去 看还能不能用
Just slam this thing in. See if it's still good.
老大
Boss…
快看那鬼东西能不能用就对了
Just see if the fucking thing works!
我们得离开这里
We need to get outta here.
三十秒之内撤离 动作快
Extraction, 30 seconds or less. Let's go, let's go!
我要问你一件事
Let me ask you somethin',
用我的甜嘴问
sweet-like…
瑞迪克 这一趟死了不少人
Lot of good men died here, Riddick.
下次我还是会不知道该不该逮捕你
Not sure how I'm supposed to overlook that. Next time.
是啊 要不是他们想把我的头装在箱子里
Yeah. Things would have been different
结果本来会不一样的
if they weren't trying to put my head in a box.
瑞迪克 你现在打算去哪
So where to now, Riddick?
算了 去他的 别告诉我 我不想知道
You know what? Fuck that. Don't tell me. I don't wanna know.
这么说吧
I'll tell you this, Johns.
每个人迟早都得回家的
Sooner or later, we all have to head home.
告诉达尔 随时为我准备好
Tell Dahl to keep it warm for me.
还有 约翰
And, Johns,
你是个虎父
you keep a strong spine.
瓦可
Vaako.
你还活着 告诉我他在哪里
You are still alive. Tell me where.
他已经不在这里了
He's no longer among us.
告诉我 我会先杀了他
Tell me, and I'll kill him first.
你误会了
You misunderstand.
瓦可 是个正直且重视荣誉的人
Vaako is a decent man who meant to honor his word.
哪怕是跟你在一起 很奇怪
Even with you, strangely.
我并不关心复仇星星球
I don't care about Furya.
我并不关心你跟他之间的协定
I don't care what the pact was between you and him.
死亡教派不容许出现异端
This faith cannot have a misbeliever
或者仁慈的领导者
or a kind heart leading it,
我已经尽力去确保…
and I have done what I have done to ensure…
太啰嗦了
Too many words.
别对我撒谎 我就不会伤害你
Never lie to me, I'll never hurt you.
我要你回答我
One word answer.
瓦可 是死是活
Is Vaako alive or dead?
都是
Both.